screamingfrog.co.uk 2019-11-22

# Disclaimer | Screaming Frog

## PRIVACY POLICY

This is the privacy policy for Screaming Frog Limited (“we” or “us” or “our”), please read it carefully because it explains how we collect and use information about you in the scenarios that are described in paragraph 3 below. By taking any of the actions referred to in paragraph 3 below, you agree that we may collect and use your information in the ways described in this privacy policy.

**1\. Who we are**

We are a limited company registered in England and Wales under company number 07277243. Our registered office is at 3 Acorn Business Centre, Northarbour Road, Portsmouth, PO6 3TH. For details of how to contact us, please refer to the contact us page at www.screamingfrog.co.uk.

If you have any questions about how we collect, store and use personal  
information, or if you have any other privacy-related questions, please contact our data protection team by any of the following means: at privacy@screamingfrog.co.uk or by post at: Data Protection Team, Screaming Frog Ltd, 6 Greys Road, Henley-on-Thames, Oxfordshire, RG9 1RY. UK

The privacy notice governs the collection, storage and use of personal information collected by Screaming Frog Ltd via our tools, website and any third parties used by us.

**2\. Dealing with Children**

We do not and will not knowingly process information from any unsupervised child  
under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, you are not permitted to interact with or provide any data via this website or via any of our tools unless you have the consent of, and are supervised by, a parent or guardian.

**3\. How we collect information**

We will collect information from you if you:

• register to buy a product; this will include your name, company name, address, email address and VAT number and payment details;  
• complete online forms, take part in surveys, write posts or comments on any message boards, enter any competitions or prize draws, download or participate in any other interactive areas that appear on our website or which we offer to you from time to time  
• provide your contact details when you register to use or access any product or service we provide  
• use our software or tools; We may check specific information relevant to your use of the software or product contained in your computer against our records to make sure the software or products are being used in accordance with our software licence agreements. This may include your username, licence key, IP address, anonymised machine id, timestamp. We may gather statistical information about the operating system and environment on which our software or product are installed; When we automatically gather data relating to crashes, bugs or issues encountered when using any of our tools or software; When you send software logs or debug reports which may contain details of sites crawled, short extracts of log files analysed and other settings  
• contact us offline for example by telephone, fax, email or post.

We also collect information about your visit to our website or use of our products or services using cookies or similar technologies (as described below).

**4\. What we use your information for**

We use your information to provide any information and services that you have requested or any products that you have ordered.

• to allow us to create an account for you  
• to allow us to receive payment for products and services provided  
• to allow us to respond to communications from you  
• to allow us to respond to support requests  
• to allow us to verify legitimate use of our software and tools  
• to notify you of product updates and fixes  
• we may use your information for marketing purposes, although we will only do so if you have specifically consented for us to do so  
• we may use and analyse the information that we collect so that we can administer, support, improve and develop our website and the products and services we offer.

Personal information is processed only in accordance with our legitimate interest in providing products and services to you and monitoring and improving the use and satisfaction of our website and tools.

**5\. The legal basis for processing personal data is:**

Contract: If you download and install our software, you are entering into a contract with us that allows you to use our software.

Legal Obligation: We are required by law to retain certain types of data, including financial records so that we can respond to a request to audit our business. If we are required to disclose any information to an official third party or authority we will only do so where we are legally obliged to.

Legitimate Interest: It is in our legitimate interest to monitor legitimate use of our products.

Consent: When you sign up or complete forms via our website, we may request your explicit consent to collect and store your personal data.

**6\. Data Storage**

Your data is stored in secure data centres located in the United Kingdom & United States of America.

Access to this data is restricted to authorised personnel only.

We will keep your information secure by taking appropriate technical and organisational measures against its unauthorised or unlawful processing and against its accidental loss, destruction or damage. 

Our software applications may, with your consent, access and store your Google user data, however, such data is only available and stored by the user, will only be used for the purposes outlined in this policy and will not be accessible or shared by us.

**7\. Transfers outside Europe**

Personal data in the European Union is protected by data protection laws but other countries do not necessarily protect your personal data in the same way. Our website and some of our products or services or parts of them may be hosted in the United States and this means that we may transfer any information which is submitted by you through the website, product or service outside the European Economic Area (which means all the EU countries plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein) (“EEA”) to the United States. When you send an email to us, this may also be stored on email servers which are hosted in the United States or outside the EU. We have taken steps to ensure that our hosting provider uses the necessary level of protection for your information but if you do not want your information to be transferred outside the EEA you should not use our website, product or service or contact us via email.  
“Cookies” are small text files which are transferred from our website, product or service and stored on your computer’s hard drive. We use a combination of cookies to help us provide you with a personalised service, and also to help make our websites, products and services better for you.

**8\. Sharing your information**

We will never sell your information to third parties.

We will never use your personal details for marketing purposes unless you have specifically consented to us doing so.

We may share your information with third party service providers who assist us in proving our services.

We have requested a Data Processing Addendum (DPA) with all service providers and have assurances that all providers will have a DPA in place within the required timescale for GDPR compliance.

We will disclose your information if we are required to by law. We may disclose your information to enforcement authorities if they ask us to, or to a third party in the context of actual or threatened legal proceedings, provided we can do so without breaching data protection laws.

**9\. Marketing**

From time to time, we may use your information to contact you with details about our products and services which we feel may be of interest to you, however, we will only do so where we have specific agreement from you to do so.

You have the right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes. If you wish to exercise these rights you can do so by sending us an email to privacy@screamingfrog.co.uk.

**10\. Data Retention**

Your data will be stored for the duration of your enquiry, contract, or dealings with us. We may be required to store your data for longer to comply with legal, contractual or compliance obligations.

**11\. What are your rights**

• you have the right, at any time and free of charge, to ask us to provide you with copies of all personal information we hold about you.  
• you have the right to ask us to amend, correct or update any personal information we hold about you.  
• you can request to opt out of any marketing communications you may receive from us.  
• you have the right to request we delete any personal information that we hold. In some cases we may not be able to stop using your personal information but, if that is the case, we will explain this to you and provide the reason.

For further information in relation to your rights, contact: privacy@screamingfrog.co.uk or write to Screaming Frog Ltd, 6 Greys Road, Henley-on-Thames, Oxfordshire, RG9 1RY. UK

**12\. Cookies and Similar Technologies**

“Cookies” are small text files which are transferred from our website, product or service and stored on your computer’s hard drive. We use a combination of cookies to help us provide you with a personalised service, and also to help make our websites, products and services better for you.

We use the following different types of cookies:

**Session Cookies**  
These are temporary cookies which are deleted when you close your browser or leave your session in the product or service. We use session cookies on our websites and in some of our products or services to identify and track users.

**Persistent Cookies**  
Persistent cookies enable our websites, product or service to “remember” who you are and to remember your preferences on our website. Persistent cookies will stay on your computer or device after you close your browser or leave your session in the product or service.

We use persistent cookies on our websites and in some of our products or services to identify and track users and to remember what is in your shopping basket (where relevant). We may also use persistent cookies and similar technologies in our products or services from time to time where this enables us to offer you certain features of the product or service or where it may help us to improve the product or service.

**Web analytics cookies and similar technologies**  
Our websites, products and services use several third-party web analytics cookies and similar technologies. These allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and see how such visitors move around the website, product or service. This helps us make our service to you better and also help us to contact you with details about our products and services which we feel may be of interest to you.

**Web beacons**  
We also use cookies and similar software known as web beacons to count users who have visited our website after clicking through from one of our advertisements on another website or in emails and to collect details of any products purchased. These web beacons collect limited information which does not identify particular individuals. It is not possible to refuse the use of web beacons. However, because they are used in conjunction with cookies, you can effectively disable them by setting your browser to restrict or block cookies.

**IP address and parameter tracking**  
We keep a record of traffic data which is logged automatically by our server, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, the website that you visited before ours, the website you visit after leaving our site. We also collect some site, product and service statistics such as access rates, page hits and page views. We are not able to identify any individual from these traffic data or site statistics alone.

**Third party technology**  
We sometimes use the technology of a third party service provider to collect information about browsing activity on certain pages of our website by tracking/identifying the IP address that you use when you access those pages. We only track/identify your IP address whilst you are using our website and do not track the IP address when you leave our website.

This third party technology will expire after you close your browser or leave your session in the product or service. Our third party service provider collects information about which organisations are accessing our website and we may use that information to contact those organisations about our products and services that we feel may be of interest.

**Change your cookie and similar technology preferences**  
You may be able to configure your browser to restrict or block cookies and similar technologies if you wish, however, if you disable those you may find this affects your ability to use certain parts of our website, products or services. For more information about cookies and instructions on how to adjust your browser settings to accept, delete or reject cookies and similar technologies, see the Internet Advertising Bureau website www.youronlinechoices.com.

**13\. Changes to our privacy policy**

We may change our privacy policy from time to time. We will always update the privacy policy on our website, so please try to read it when you visit the website.

**14\. Other Sites**

If you follow a link from our website, product or service to another site or service, this policy will no longer apply. We are not responsible for the information handling practices of third party sites or services and we encourage you to read the privacy policies appearing on those sites or services. 

**15\. Right to complain**

If you believe that we are not holding your information correctly or are unhappy at any dealings with us regarding your information you may complain to the Information Commissioners Office. You can do this via their website https://ico.org.uk/concerns or by calling 0303 123 1113.

## WEBSITE DISCLAIMER:

These are the terms and conditions (“the terms”) governing the use of this website (“the Website”) which is wholly owned by Screaming Frog Limited (“the Company”). These terms apply to each user and/or visitor to the Website and are governed by English law.

**PROPRIETOR AND PROPRIETARY INFORMATION**  
Information on this Website is the property of the Company. The materials contained in this site are protected by copyright law. The contents of the Website are available to any user and/or visitor for personal reference only and may not be reproduced in any manner whatsoever either in whole or in part without the prior written permission of the Company, its authorised agents or representatives.  
The Company reserves the right in its absolute discretion:  
(a) to add to or remove any material from the Website or to amend, alter, redesign or change anything contained in or on it at any time; and  
(b) to monitor, suspend, revoke, or otherwise limit access to the Website at any time.

**NO WARRANTIES**  
The use of this Website is at the visitor’s or user’s own personal risk. The Company does not warrant the content, accuracy or veracity of any material or other information on the Website nor does it warrant that the Website is free from errors, faults, viruses or other computer or data-corrupting or data-damaging material.

The Website contains links to other sites or addresses on the web. External sites are not part of the Website and do not belong to the Company. The Company does not approve or endorse other websites nor is it responsible for their content.

Descriptions of, or references to products, services or publications within the Website do not constitute or imply their endorsement or recommendation in any way by the Company, its employees or contractors. No reference in the Website to any specific product, process, or service by trade name, trademark, manufacturer, or otherwise, shall be used for advertising or product endorsement purposes.

**EXCLUSION OF LIABILITY**  
To the maximum extent permitted by law the Company excludes liability for any loss, claim, damages or any special, consequential, exemplary or punitive damages (whether directly or indirectly incurred) of any kind arising out of or in connection with any visitor’s or user’s access to, or use of the Website, or any material thereon, whether based in contract, tort or whether negligent or otherwise, even in the Company has been advised of the possibility of such damage..

Last updated 7th November 2019
